오빠, 그 혜성인가 뭔가는
언제 시작해?
Ross, when's this comet thing start?
원래 시작하긴
칠십억 년 전에 했지
Well, technically, it started
7 billion years ago.
알았어, 알았어
가르치려 들지 않을게
Okay. Fine, I'll stop.
No teaching, okay?
그냥 하늘을 가로지르는
아름다운 빛을 보는 거야
We'll just watch the pretty light
streaking across the sky.
알았어?
Okay?
공식이름은 밥스틴 킹이지
알았어! 그만할게!
Whose official name is Bapstein-King.
Okay! Okay!
저기 있다, 저거 봐!
There it is. Oh, look at that!
자연은 놀랍지 않니?
Isn't Mother Nature amazing?
저건 비행기야
That's a plane.
알았다, 땅콩 1700봉지가
하늘 높이 날아가는 것도
Well, all right, 1700 bags
of peanuts flying that high...
꽤 놀라운 일이지
that's pretty amazing too.
- 내 아파트도 보일까?
- 아니, 안 보여
-I wonder if you can see my apartment.
-No, you can't.
- 뭐라구?
- 몰라
-What?
-I don't know.
저 별들 좀 봐
Man, look at all those stars.
무한한 우주...
정말 놀랍지 않니?
Infinite space. It really makes you
wonder, doesn't it?
- 또 뭐가 놀라운지 알아?
- 뭔데?
-Know what else makes you wonder?
-What?
저 여자 가슴 좀 봐
Check out the rack on that chick.
The One Where They're Up All Night
We've been out here for two hours...
벌써 두 시간 지났는데
and we haven't seen any
stupid comets. Can we go now?
혜성 구경도 못 했다
이제 그만 가도 돼?
I mean, Chandler's getting chilly.
챈들러가 춥대
나 안 추운데
No, I'm not.
그럼 왜 모니카
자켓 입고 있는 거야?
Then why are you wearing
Monica's jacket?
그냥 예쁘니까!
Because it's flattering!
어서, 모니카, 가자
Come on, Monica. Come on, Monica.
- 영화를 빌렸거든, 가 볼래
- 나도 영화나 볼래
-We're going too. We got a movie.
-I won't say no to a movie.
피비, 우리 둘이서만
있고 싶거든
Oh, Phoebe, we just actually
wanted to be alone.
- 나도 여길 피하고 싶어
- 알았어
-Sh. Get me out of here.
-Oh, okay.
- 로스
- 왜?
-Hey, Ross.
-What?
- 이것 좀 봐
- 혜성이야?
-Check it out.
-Is it the comet?
아니, 벌레가 타르에
달라붙어 있잖아
No. Look, there's a bug
stuck in tar right here.
I can't believe..
기가 막히는군
I bring you to see
the Bapstein-King comet...
자연의 경이로운 현상인
밥스틴 킹 혜성을
one of nature's
most spectacular phenomena...
보려주려고
여길 데려왔더니
and all you care about are bugs
stuck in tar and some woman.
기껏 벌레나 어떤 여자
타령이나 하고
You know, there's two women, dude.
두 여자였어, 이 친구야
Show me where.
어디 있다고?
Okay. Right up here.
좋아, 바로 저 위
Joey, where's the pipe
that was holding the door open?
문 안 닫히게 받쳐뒀던
파이프는 어디 갔냐?
I don't know.
내가 아냐?
Yeah, I do.
그래, 안다
-Joey!
-What? Hey, don't look at me!
- 조이!
- 뭐? 왜 나한테 그래?
You wanted to come up here and look
for some stupid Burger King comet.
멍청한 버거킹 혜성 보자고
한 게 누군데 그래?
It's called the
Bapstein-King comet, okay?
밥스틴 킹 혜성이야
알았어?
Hey, Bapstein was a very
well-respected astronomer from..
밥스틴은 아주 유명한
천문학자로서...
No!
그만 둬!
-Monica.
-She's sleeping.
- 모니카
- 모니카 자
I know. Just a quick question.
알아, 한 가지 물어볼게
Which one was Deep Impact
and which one was Armageddon?
어느 게 딥 임팩트고
어느 게 아마게돈이지?
Deep Impact was the one
with Robert Duvall.
딥 임팩트는
로버트 듀발 나온 거고
Armageddon is what's going
to happen to you if you wake me up.
아마게돈은 날 깨우면
자기가 겪게 될 일이지
Sorry, I just can't sleep.
미안해, 잠이 안 와
자기가 읽던 책 어딨지?
꽃 달린 모자쓰고
Where's that book you're reading
with two women who are ice-skating...
두 여자가 스케이트
타는 거 말야
and wearing those hats
with the flowers on it.
그 표지를
보기만 하면 난...
Because every time I look
at that cover, I'm like..
거실에 있어
거기 램프도 있고
It's in the living room,
where there's also a light...
거기서 읽으면
아무도 정강이 안 차
and no one will
kick you in the shin.
뭐?
What?
우주선이면 안 되는데
Please don't be a spaceship.
다행이다
Oh, thank God.
어떻게 소리가 나니
코드를 뽑았는데!
How could you be beeping?
I just disconnected you!
배터리도 빼 버렸는데!
어떻...? 말 끊지 마!
I took out your battery! How can..?
Don't interrupt me!
레이첼! 모니카!
Monica! Monica!
얘들아!
Come on!
돌아 버리겠네!
I can't believe this!
좋아, 내려가려면
한 가지 방법밖에 없군
All right, well, I guess we know
what we have to do to get down.
그래, 어쩔 수 없다
Yeah, I guess we don't have a choice.
도와줘요!
제발 도와줘요!
Help us! Please, help us!
지붕에 갇혔는데
못 내려가겠어요!
We're stuck up on the roof,
and we can't get down!
로스
Ross.
난 비상계단으로 내려갈
생각이었는데
I was thinking we'd just
go down the fire escape.
알아, 아직 안 끝났어
I know. I wasn't finished.
걱정 말아요!
But don't worry!
비상계단으로
내려갈 거니까!
We're gonna go down the fire escape!
Sh!
I'm sorry, I thought I'd make some
warm milk and it would help me sleep.
미안해, 따뜻한 우유 마시면
잠이 올 것 같아서
With a wok?
후라이팬으로 마시게?
My boring book didn't
put you to sleep?
잠 자려고 책
읽는다고 했잖아
It got interesting.
재미있어지잖아
Damn you, Oprah!
젠장할 오프라!
Here, let me make the milk.
I'm up anyway.
내가 우유 데워줄게
나도 잠 깼어
You know what we could do
now that we're up?
우리 둘 다 깼으니
뭘 하면 좋을지 알아?
We could just talk
to each other all night long.
밤새 이야기하자
Like when we were first dating.
It'd be fun.
처음 데이트할 때처럼
재미있을 거야
-Okay, that does sound fun.
-Yeah.
- 그래, 재미있겠다
- 신난다
So how bummed were you
when the second sister died, huh?
둘째 언니 죽으니
기분이 어땠어?
The second sister dies?!
둘째 언니가 죽어?
No.
아니
No, I was talking
about the book I was reading.
아니, 내가 읽던
내 책 얘기한 거야
The second sister dies in
Archie and Jughead Double Digest?
아치와 저그해드 만화에서
둘째 언니가 죽은 것?
That's correct.
그래, 그거
Want to go in the bedroom?
It's more comfortable.
침실로 갈까?
거기가 더 편하잖아
-Sure.
-Okay.
- 좋아
- 그래
Oh, wait, did you send
those contracts to Milan?
잠깐, 자기 밀라노에
계약서 보냈어?
If this is your idea of sexy talk...
이걸 야한 얘기라고
한다면...
Did you overnight
the contracts I gave you?
내가 준 계약서
보냈냐니까?
What contracts?
무슨 계약서?
Please tell me this is just one
of your jokes that I don't get.
제발 이 것도 자기
썰렁한 농담이라고 해줘
Like what?
무슨 농담?
Like the thing when you
put the phone in your pants?
자기 바지에 전화기
넣는 장난 같은 거 말야
Tag, I'm serious.
This isn't funny.
태그, 진짜야
장난 아니라고
Those contracts had to go out today.
그 계약서 오늘 보내야 돼
You didn't give me any contracts.
나한테 안 줬어
Yes, I did. I put a little
Post-it on it that said:
줬잖아
그 위에 메모까지 적어서
"Must go out today," and I
underlined "today" three times.
'오늘 중 발송 요망'이라고
'오늘'에 세 번이나 밑 줄 치고
Then I put a little heart in the
corner so I wouldn't seem too bossy.
그 다음에 상사 티 안 내려고
하트그림 그려서
You never gave them to me.
안 줬다니까
If we went to the office, you would see
those contracts sitting on your desk.
사무실 함께 가보면
자기 책상에 놓인 걸 발견 할거야
No, I'd see you looking embarrassed
because they are not on my desk.
아니, 내 책상에 없어서
괜히 민망할 걸
Maybe I'm embarrassed because you
talk on the phone with your crotch.
자기 바지에 전화길 넣어서
민망하다는 거겠지
You want to go to the office now?
지금 가볼까?
Come on, it's late.
We're not going down to the office.
너무 늦었어
지금 어떻게 가?
Yeah, I understand. I wouldn't
want to be proved wrong either.
그래, 나라도 내가
틀렸단 걸 보이기 싫겠지
All right, get your coat!
좋아, 코트 입어!
Oh! When did you unhook this?
Nice work!
이거 언제 풀었어?
솜씨 좋은데
It won't go down any further.
It's stuck.
이게 더 이상 안 내려 가
We'll just have to jump.
그럼 뛰어내리자
Now, we're gonna have
to make sure to land...
뛰어내릴 때
저 얼음더미
to the right of that
patch of ice, okay?
오른쪽으로
내려가야 돼, 알았지?
Not hit the dumpster
on the other side.
반대편 쓰레기더미도
피해야 되고
And try to avoid that weird
brownish-red stuff in the middle.
가운데 불그레하고 갈색 빛
이상한 것도 피하고
So when you get down there...
일단 네가 내려가면
you go up to the roof
and you let me in.
옥상으로 가서
문 열어 줘
-Wait a minute. I have to do it?
-You'll be fine.
- 뭐? 나더러 하라고?
- 괜찮을 거야
It'll be just like
bungee jumping, you know?
번지점프하는 거나 같아
But instead of bouncing back up,
you won't.
다시 튀어오르지
않는 것만 빼면
Well, what if I smack
my head on the concrete?
시멘트바닥에 머리를
찧으면 어쩌고?
Well, I'm not gonna lie to you, Joey.
It's a possibility.
그래 거짓말은 안 할게
그럴 수도 있어
I don't know. Tell you what,
let's flip to see who does it.
글쎄, 동전 던지기로
누가 할지 정하자
-You call it in the air, all right?
-Oh, all right.
- 던질 테니 말해
- 알았어
-Can you see what it is?
-No.
- 뭔지 보여?
- 아니
-Okay. Well, you be careful.
-No, Ross, stop it.
- 그래, 조심해라
- 안 돼, 로스, 멈춰
I'm not jumping.
난 못 뛰어내려
Look, I have an audition tomorrow,
and I can't go if I break my leg.
내일 오디션 있는데
다리 부러지면 어떡해
Well, I'm not jumping. I have a son.
He won't have a father if I die.
나도 안 뛰어내려
내 아들 고아 만들기 싫어
So it looks like we're even.
그럼 같은 처지네
Okay, so this wire...
좋아, 이 선이
is connected to this wire,
which plugs into here.
이 선과 연결돼서
플러그와 이어졌고
Okay, so to get the beeping to stop,
all I have to do...
그러니 삐 소리를
멈추게 하려면...
Okay.
Well done, Phoebe.
잘 했어, 피비
What do you want from me?!
대체 원하는게 뭐야?
Here's your milk.
What should we talk about?
여기 우유
무슨 얘길 하고 싶어?
What? What? What?
뭐야? 뭐?
Oh, were you sleeping, sweetie?
I'm sorry. Here.
자고 있었어?
미안해, 자 마셔
Okay. Feel free to look...
실컷 봐
but I'm telling you
those contracts are not here.
그렇지만 이 책상에
계약서는 없어
어떻게 알아?
이렇게 엉망인데
How could you know?
Look at this mess, Tag.
이것 좀 봐
정리정돈 좀 해
This is what I'm saying.
You have to be more organized.
신문도 있고
잡지도 있고...이런!
You've got newspapers,
you've got magazines, you.. Oh!
이 아가씬 누구야?
And who's this chippy?
자기한텐 좀 어려보이네
A little young for you, but whatever.
내 동생인데
That's my sister.
그래?
교정기 예쁘다
Really? Very cute braces.
그나저나
계속 찾기나 해
Anyway, you know what?
The point is, Tag, start looking...
분명히 자기 책상에
있을 테니까
because you're gonna find
those contracts on your desk.
언제 나한테 줬어?
아침, 오후?
So when do you imagine you gave
them to me? Morning or afternoon?
오후에, 젤너 부장님이
점심 후 사무실로 오셔서
In the afternoon. Mr. Zelner
came into my office after lunch...
내 책상에 놔뒀고
내가 메모를 붙였지
he put them on my desk,
and then I put a Post-it on it...
이렇게 말야
that said:
'오늘 중 발송 요망'
"Must go out today."
그러니까 계속
찾아보란 말이야
So you just keep looking
in there, all right?
여기 없어
They're not here.
이상하네
Puzzler.
정말 이상해
Bit of a puzzle.
복사실에 가 봐
아마 거기 놔뒀나보지
Why don't you check the copy room?
Maybe the contracts are in there.
- 그걸 내가 왜 거기 놔둬?
- 나도 모르지
-How could I have left them there?
-I don't know.
자기 거시긴 어떻게
전화를 거는데?
How can your genitals
make phone calls?
사람일은 모르니까
어서 가 봐
Okay? It's not a perfect world.
Just go, please?
- 알았어
- 고마워
-Fine.
-Thank you.
여보세요?
Hello?
이해가 안 돼요
I still don't get it.
아직 안 자?
You still awake?
응, 자기는?
Yeah. You?
내가 방금 그 질문
했잖아, 그렇지?
You do know that was me
that just said that, right?
있잖아
Hey.
우리 둘 다 안 자니까...
As long as we're both up...
그래서?
Yeah?
설마 거실 청소하잔 건
아니겠지
I hope you're not thinking
about cleaning the living room.
배고파 죽겠네, 내가
저녁때 정신이 나갔지
Man, I'm starving. What the hell
was I thinking at dinner?
'수프요, 샐러드요?'
둘 다 시켰어야지
"Do you want soup or salad?"
Both, always order both.
보니까 이 집엔
아무도 없는 것 같다
You know, I'm looking,
and I don't think anyone's home here.
그러니 창문을 깨고
들어가서
I say we just break the window...
지나간 다음에
crawl through...
나중에 설명해주지 뭐
and you know, explain later.
- 아무도 없어?
- 없는 것 같은데
-No one's home?
-I don't think so.
계세요?
Hello?
네가 일단 저길 들어가면...
So when you get in there...
좋아, 여기서 헤어지자
Okay. This is where
you and I part ways.
시끄러운 것!
Noisy bitch!
뭐? 뭐하는 거야?
Oh, what? What are you doing?
방금 무슨 일이 있었는지 알아?
Do you know what just happened?
그래, 섹스 끝내고
잠자리에 들었잖아
Yeah. We had sex
and then we fell asleep.
아냐, 섹스하는 도중에
No. We were in the middle of sex...
자기가 잠든 거야
and you fell asleep.
아냐, 그럴 리 없어
No. No, that's not true.
얼마나 좋았는데
No, best time ever.
자기 끝내줬어
Yeah. You rock my world.
- 모니카?
- 뭐?
-Monica?
-What?
최고의 서비스를 하고
있었는데 놓치다니
I was giving you some of
my best moves, and you missed it.
그러니 제발 일어나서
제대로 하자
So please wake up
so we can do it right.
알았어, 준비됐어
Okay. Okay. I'm ready.
- 자, 시작해
- 알았어
-Come on, big fella.
-Okay.
- 서비스 잘해 봐
- 알았어
-Give me the good stuff.
-Yeah.
안 돼, 잠들지 마
No, no, no. Don't fall asleep.
커피 좀 타다줄께
Okay, I'm going
to make you some coffee.
부엌에 커피 가루나
안 쏟을까 몰라
Well, I probably won't spill coffee
grounds all over the kitchen floor.
나 깼어, 깼다고
Okay, I'm up. I'm up.
커피 좀 가져왔는데...
Hi. I got you some coffee to..
그래서 찾았어?
So you got anything for me?
- 못 찾았어
- 이런
-Still no luck.
-Oh, my God.
책상과 서랍
전부 다 뒤져봤어?
You checked your entire desk
and all the drawers?
- 다시 뒤져?
- 그랬음 좋겠는데
-Want me to check again?
-I wish you would.
좋아, 거긴 없네
Well, no, it's not in there.
그럼 저 서랍은?
How about that drawer?
여기도 없는데 자기
사무실에 있지 않을까?
Well, it's not out here.
Any chance it could be in your office?
몰라
I don't know.
어디 한 번 보지
I mean, let me check.
찾았어?
Any luck?
잠깐 사무실에서 볼까?
See you in my office for a minute?
찾았네!
You found them!
레이첼 탓 안 할게
I'm not even gonna gloat.
- 찾았으니 다행이라고...
- 자기가 갖다뒀지
-I'm just really relieved it's..
-You put these on my desk.
- 아니
- 그래?
-I did not.
-Oh, really?
그럼 이게 발이 달려서
So they left your bottom drawer...
자기 책상 서랍에서 나와
내 책상으로 왔나?
crawled across the floor,
then jumped onto my desk?
내 책상 서랍에 있던 건
어떻게 알아?
How did you know
they were in my bottom drawer?
자기 정말 멋있다
I am so hot for you right now.
맙소사!
어떻게 다시 돌아왔지?
Oh, my God!
How did you get back here?
피비 부페이양?
Phoebe Buffay?
화재 경보기?
Fire Alarm?
안녕하세요, 소방관 아저씨
무슨 일이죠?
Oh, hi, Officer Fireman.
Can I help you?
쓰레기통에서
경보길 찾았어요
Your fire alarm was in the trash.
- 제거 아닌데요
- 맞아요
-That's not mine.
-Yes, it is.
How do you know?
- 어떻게 알아요?
- 다음에 뭘 버릴 땐
If you dump a fire alarm,
don't use a blanket that says:
'모니카 거 아니고 피비 것임'
이라고 쓴 담요는 쓰지 말아요
"Property of Phoebe Buffay,
not Monica."
영장 있어요?
Do you have a search warrant?
여긴 미국인 걸로 아는데요
Because the last time I checked,
this was still America.
다시 붙여놔요
떼는 건 불법이에요
Please reattach it.
It's illegal to disconnect them.
좋아요, 그런데 어떻게
끄는지 알려 주시겠어요?
Fine. But please, God, tell me
how to stop it from going off?
재작동 버튼을 눌러요
Press the reset button.
재작동 버튼이 있어요?
정말 고마워요
There's a reset button?
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
재작동 버튼이 있었군
Oh. There's a reset button?
세상에!
My God!
난 왜 못 봤지?
Why didn't I see that?
재작동 버튼, 재작동 버튼
Reset button. Reset button.
어디 있는 거야?
아, 여기 있네! 이런!
Where is there a reset button?
Oh, here it is! Oh!
-Okay, you have a good grip?
-Yeah.
- 좋아, 꽉 잡았지?
- 응
I'm gonna start to climb down you now.
그럼 내려간다
-All right, just hurry up.
-Okay.
- 빨리 하기나 해
- 알았어
Now, should I climb down your front
so we're face to face...
얼굴 마주 보고
앞으로 내려갈까
or should I climb down
your back so we're...
아니면 엉덩이와
마주보게
butt to face?
뒤에서 내려갈까?
-Face to face.
-I like face to face.
- 앞으로 내려와
- 그게 나을 것 같다
-Okay, here I come.
-All right.
- 좋아, 간다
- 그래
Oh, my.. How much do you weigh, Ross?
몸무게가 얼마냐, 로스?
I prefer not to answer. I'm still
carrying a little holiday weight.
묻지마, 크리스마스때
찐 살 아직 못 뺐어
When we talked about face to face...
앞으로 내려온다고 했을 때
I don't think we thought it
all the way through.
이렇게 내려올 줄은
생각 못 했다
-What do you want me to do?
-Just shimmy down me and drop.
- 그럼 어쩌란 말야?
- 그냥 뛰어내려
-Hi.
- 안녕
You know, maybe I should hang,
and you should climb down me.
내가 매달려 있을 테니
네가 내려가라
Yeah? Maybe we should talk
about that for a little while!
그래? 지금
그런 얘기 할 때야?
-It still looks pretty far.
-It's not that far. Just drop.
- 꽤 높아보여
- 별로 안 높아, 뛰어내려
Do not rush me!
보채지 마!
My pants are starting to come down,
and I'm not wearing any underwear.
바지 내려온단 말야
속옷도 안 입었는데
My ankle! I really hurt my ankle!
발목 다쳤어!
I think I twisted it when..
A quarter!
아마 접질린 것 같...
와, 동전이다!
자기 정말 대단했어
That really was
some of your best work.
내가 뭐랬어?
I told you.
이럴 수가...
I can't believe it.
두 시간 후면 아파 못 간다고
회사에 전화해야 돼
I've only got two hours
until I call in sick for work.
난 7분 후에 일어나야 돼
I have to be up in seven minutes.
어떻게 생각할 지 모르지만
7분이 남았다면...
Well, you're not gonna believe this,
but if you have seven minutes...
정말?
Really?
하고 싶어?
You want to?
응, 자기가 청소기 돌려
내가 가구 닦을께
You get the vacuum cleaner.
I'll get the furniture polish.